<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
        <origin>USDA Forest Service</origin>
        <pubdate>20171030</pubdate>
        <title>Monitoring Trends in Burn Severity assessment of Event ID - nv4102211692120160702</title>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>https://www.mtbs.gov/</onlink>
        <onlink>https://doi.org/10.5066/P9IED7RZ</onlink>
        <lworkcit>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Jeff Eidenshink</origin>
            <origin>Brian Schwind</origin>
            <origin>Ken Brewer</origin>
            <origin>Zhi-Liang Zhu</origin>
            <origin>Brad Quayle</origin>
            <origin>Stephen Howard</origin>
            <pubdate>2007</pubdate>
            <title>A Project for Monitoring Trends in Burn Severity</title>
            <geoform>publication</geoform>
            <othercit>Fire Ecology Special Issue
Vol. 3, No. 1, 2007</othercit>
            <onlink>https://www.mtbs.gov/sites/default/files/inline-files/Eidenshink-final.pdf</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </lworkcit>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The Monitoring Trends in Burn Severity (MTBS) Program assesses the frequency, extent, and magnitude (size and severity) of all large wildland fires (wildfires and prescribed fires) in the conterminous United States (CONUS), Alaska, Hawaii, and Puerto Rico for the period 1984 and beyond. All fires reported as greater than 1,000 acres in the western U.S. and greater than 500 acres in the eastern U.S. are mapped across all ownerships. MTBS produces a series of geospatial and tabular data for analysis at a range of spatial, temporal, and thematic scales and are intended to meet a variety of information needs that require consistent data about fire effects through space and time. This map layer is a thematic raster image of an individual MTBS burn severity fire, occurring during calendar year 2016. Fires omitted from this mapped inventory are those where suitable satellite imagery was not available or fires were not discernable from available imagery.</abstract>
      <purpose>The data generated by MTBS will be used to identify national trends in burn severity, providing information necessary to monitor the effectiveness of the National Fire Plan and Healthy Forests Restoration Act. MTBS is sponsored by the Wildland Fire Leadership Council (WFLC), a multi-agency oversight group responsible for implementing and coordinating the National Fire Plan and Federal Wildland Fire Management Policies. The MTBS project objective is to provide consistent, 30 meter spatial resolution burn severity data and burned area delineations that will serve four primary user groups including: 1. National policies and policy makers such as the National Fire Plan and WFLC which require information about long-term trends in burn severity and recent burn severity impacts within vegetation types, fuel models, condition classes, and land management activities. 2. Field management units that benefit from mid to broad scale GIS-ready maps and data for pre- and post-fire assessment and monitoring. Field units that require finer scale burn severity data will also benefit from increased efficiency, reduced costs, and data consistency by starting with MTBS data. 3. Existing databases from other comparably scaled programs, such as Fire Regime and Condition Class (FRCC) within LANDFIRE, that will benefit from MTBS data for validation and updating of geospatial data sets. 4. Academic and government agency research entities interested in fire severity data over significant geographic and temporal extents.</purpose>
      <supplinf>The MTBS Event-ID is generated by combining several attributes taken from the fire ignition location and start date. The MTBS Event-ID is constructed from the two letter state abbreviation, the decimal degree latitude and longitude, both carried to the third decimal place without the decimal point (if less than 100 degrees the longitude is padded with a leading '0'), and the start date formatted as YYYYMMDD (e.g., TX2672909780020110102).

Fire Information 
MTBS Event ID: nv4102211692120160702
Fire Name (if known): HOT POT
Date of Fire: July 02, 2016
Type of Assessment: Initial
Acres within Fire Perimeter: 120015

Pre-Fire Sensor, Date, Scene ID: Landsat 8 OLI, 2016-06-22, 804103220160622
Post-Fire Sensor, Date, Scene ID: Landsat 8 OLI, 2016-07-08, 804103220160708

See https://www.mtbs.gov/ for project information and data access. 
Refer to https://www.mtbs.gov/contact for additional support. </supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>July 02, 2016</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <descgeog>MTBS burn severity</descgeog>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-117.06565</westbc>
        <eastbc>-116.70245</eastbc>
        <northbc>41.23441</northbc>
        <southbc>40.93354</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Wildfire</themekey>
        <themekey>Prescribed fire</themekey>
        <themekey>Fire occurrence</themekey>
        <themekey>Landsat</themekey>
        <themekey>Differenced normalized burn ratio</themekey>
        <themekey>Wildland fire</themekey>
        <themekey>Normalized burn ratio</themekey>
        <themekey>MTBS</themekey>
        <themekey>Burned area</themekey>
        <themekey>Burn severity</themekey>
        <themekey>Fire location</themekey>
        <themekey>Location</themekey>
        <themekey>Sentinel</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>Common geographic areas</placekt>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
        <placekey>Continental U.S.</placekey>
        <placekey>Alaska</placekey>
        <placekey>Hawaii</placekey>
        <placekey>Puerto Rico</placekey>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placekt>Common geographic areas</placekt>
        <placekey>US</placekey>
        <placekey>CONUS</placekey>
        <placekey>AK</placekey>
        <placekey>HI</placekey>
        <placekey>PR</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>There are no restrictions on use, except for reasonable and proper acknowledgement of information sources.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>MTBS Project Manager</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>47914 252nd Street</address>
          <city>Sioux Falls</city>
          <state>SD</state>
          <postal>57198</postal>
          <country>US</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-252-4547</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>https://www.mtbs.gov/contact</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>Monitoring Trends in Burn Severity Project (U.S. Geological Survey and USDA Forest Service). U.S. Geological Survey (physical address): 47914 252nd Street: Sioux Falls, SD, USA, 57198. Phone: 800-252-4547. USDA Forest Service (physical address): 125 South State Street, Suite 7105: Salt Lake City, UT, USA, 84138. Phone: 801-975-3800.</datacred>
    <native>ERDAS Imagine, and ESRI ArcGIS</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>MTBS analysts examine the differenced Normalized Burn Ratio (dNBR) image for each fire in the context of remote sensing spectral data and any ancillary information available to the analyst. dNBR image data for each fire are thresholded into classes representing unburned areas; areas of low, moderate, high burn severities; and areas of increased vegetation response. Analysts follow guidelines established by subject matter experts in order to maintain consistency in discerning burn severity thresholds from fire to fire and minimize subjectivity.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>No tests for logical consistency have been performed on this map layer.</logic>
    <complete>Data completeness reflects the availability of fire occurrence information and/or availability of suitable imagery (including Landsat TM, Landsat ETM+, Landsat OLI, Sentinel 2A, and Sentinel 2B), and the current progression of processing by the MTBS program in the specified state or geographic region. In some areas, fires smaller than the specified MTBS fire size criteria may be present. These fires were mapped using MTBS mapping protocols to meet the data/information needs of other unrelated programs but are included in the MTBS database.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Each image used to create the burn severity assessment (utilizing Landsat TM, Landsat ETM+, Landsat OLI, Sentinel 2A, and Sentinel 2B), was precision terrain-corrected using 3-arc-second digital terrain elevation data, and georegistered using ground control points. This resulted in a root mean square registration error of less than 1 pixel (30 meters).</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>N/A</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>For a detailed definition and discussion on the processing and production of MTBS geospatial data, please refer to https://www.mtbs.gov. A synopsis of the production of this layer is provided below.

MTBS burn severity class data are spatially derived from data obtained from suitable imagery (including Landsat TM, Landsat ETM+, Landsat OLI, Sentinel 2A, and Sentinel 2B). A pre- and a post-fire scene are used to create a dNBR image. The continuous dNBR image portrays the variations of burn severity within the fire. In exceptional circumstances, a suitable pre-fire image may not be available to generate a dNBR . Consequently, analysis and assessment is conducted using the post-fire Normalized Burn Ratio (NBR) image only.

The MTBS mapping approach has consistently occurred in five primary steps:

1. Fire Occurrence Data Compilation
2. Scene Selection and Image Pre-processing
3. Perimeter Delineation
4. Burn Severity Interpretation
5. Data Distribution

1. Fire Occurrence Data Compilation:

Historically, MTBS compiled fire occurrence data from a number of federal and state databases that maintained little consistency in standards for content, geospatial accuracy, and nomenclature. These datasets were then filtered and standardized internally by MTBS staff in an effort to reduce duplication of incident records reported by multiple agencies, and to resolve gross geospatial inaccuracies that were commonly found in the source data.

In recent years, significant improvements have been made to streamline the reporting procedures and data exchange for land management agencies in their creation and maintenance of fire occurrence data. Specifically, the Integrated Reporting of Wildland-Fire Information (IRWIN) Project has provided an end-to-end fire reporting system focused on the goals of reducing redundant data entry, identifying authoritative data sources, and improving the consistency, accuracy, and availability of operational data. Through a multi-year phased approach, the IRWIN Project is tasked with identifying and integrating fire occurrence data from a number of different sources and applications.

Fire occurrence data from IRWIN are routinely ingested into a database maintained by MTBS and other postfire mapping programs, and currently make up the bulk of the records used by MTBS to identify candidate fires for mapping. More information on IRWIN can be found at: https://www.forestsandrangelands.gov/WFIT/applications/IRWIN/index.shtml. </procdesc>
        <procdate>20200818</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>2. Scene Selection and Image Pre-processing: 

For fire events that meet the minimum size requirement for MTBS mapping, corresponding Landsat and Sentinel scenes are selected based upon the reported location and ignition date. After an initial review and determination of the appropriate assessment strategy: initial, extended or single scene, candidate prefire and postfire scenes are reviewed and downloaded using tools and applications developed by U.S. Geological Survey Earth Resources Observation and Science (EROS) Center, such as Earth Explorer and GloVis. Limitations due to scene quality are common in areas prone to cloud cover (e.g., the Southeast United States). Other atmospheric conditions such as smoke from active fires, terrain shadows and other obscurations also reduce the number of candidate scenes. In addition, northern latitudes are subject to a shorter period of optimal scene selection due to undesirable sun angles in the fall and a shorter growing season.

Downloaded scenes are processed to generate top-of-atmosphere reflectance images according to existing USGS-EROS protocols that include geometric (including terrain correction) and radiometric correction through the Landsat Ground Processing System process. Prior to processing the imagery into a burn severity product, prefire and postfire images are inspected for co-registration accuracy and corrected if spatial differences are noted.

Using the reflectance imagery, a Normalized Burn Ratio (NBR) image is generated for each prefire and postfire scene as the normalized difference between middle infrared and near infrared wavelength bands and then differenced to create a dNBR image. A relativized dNBR (RdNBR) is also calculated to evaluate potential limitations of dNBR to characterize fire severity on low biomass sites and potentially enhance inter-fire comparability of the results at larger ecological scales. Processing the Landsat or Sentinel image data to NBR, dNBR and RdNBR is a straightforward series of calculations relying principally on automated production sequences.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20200818</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>3. Perimeter Delineation:

The burned area boundary is delineated by on-screen interpretation of the reflectance imagery, NBR, dNBR and/or RdNBR images. The mapping analyst digitizes a perimeter to include any detectable fire area derived from these images. Clouds, cloud shadows, snow or other anomalies intersecting the fire area are also delineated and used to generate a mask later in the workflow. The mapping analyst may inspect and/or modify an existing burn area boundary and mask sourced from a reputable fire occurrence dataset or fire detection model when available. To ensure consistency and high spatial precision, digitization and inspection is performed at on-screen display scales between 1:24000 and 1:50000.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20200818</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>4. Burn Severity Interpretation:

The process of developing a categorical burn severity product is subjective and is dependent on analyst interpretation. The analyst evaluates the dNBR data range and determines where significant thresholds exist in the data to discriminate between burn severity classes. Interpretations are conducted on the NBR, dNBR and RdNBR data, aided by the prefire and postfire imagery, and analyst experience with fire behavior and effects in a given ecological setting. Where available, high resolution imagery is visually inspected to provide confidence in selecting the burn severity thresholds.

Thresholding dNBR data into thematic class values results in an intuitive map depicting a manageable number of ecologically significant classes (typically 4 to 7 class values). There are uncertainties in this approach stemming from analyst subjectivity and limited or no plot data to guide threshold selection. Ecological significance of burn severity classes will also likely vary across regions and landscapes and one set of thresholds cannot be expected to apply equally well to all analysis objectives and management issues.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20200818</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>5. Data Distribution:

The primary access point for acquiring MTBS data is through the program website: https://www.mtbs.gov. There you will find an interactive viewer which allows users to search for and download individual fire data in addition to direct download options for state and national data products. Connection information is also provided for those interested in using web map services.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20200818</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>
      <rowcount>930.0</rowcount>
      <colcount>1207.7333333333333</colcount>
      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Albers Conical Equal Area</mapprojn>
          <albers>
            <stdparll>29.5</stdparll>
            <stdparll>45.5</stdparll>
            <longcm>-96.0</longcm>
            <latprjo>23.0</latprjo>
            <feast>0</feast>
            <fnorth>0</fnorth>
          </albers>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>30</absres>
            <ordres>30</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983 (NAD 83)</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.2572221010042</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Fire perimeter shapefile</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Table containing attribute information associated with the data set.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Producer Defined</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Event_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Event ID.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>The Event-ID is generated by combining several attributes taken from the fire ignition location and start date. The Event-ID is constructed from the two letter state abbreviation, the decimal degree latitude and longitude, both carried to the third decimal place without the decimal point (if less than 100 degrees the longitude is padded with a leading '0'), and the start date formatted as YYYYMMDD (e.g., TX2672909780020110102).</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>irwinID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>IRWIN ID.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>IRWIN Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>The IRWIN ID is a unique identifier created by the Integrated Reporting of Wildland-Fire Information (IRWIN) service. Example: 5DF6471C-07B0-4EA0-8188-4F83B18A47F8</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Incid_Name</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of fire (UNNAMED if not identifiable from source fire occurrence databases).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
        <udom>Example: Tank Hollow</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Incid_Type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Documented type of fire (WF: Wildfire, Rx: Prescribed Fire; UNK:Unknown).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Wildfire</edomv>
            <edomvd>An unplanned, unwanted wildland fire including unauthorized human-caused fires, escaped wildland fire use events, escaped prescribed fire projects, and all other wildland fires where the objective is to put the fire out.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Prescribed fire</edomv>
            <edomvd>Any fire intentionally ignited by management actions in accordance with applicable laws, policies, and regulations to meet specific objectives.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Wildland fire use</edomv>
            <edomvd>An event dealing with the management of a naturally ignited wildland fire to accomplish specific prestated resource management objectives in predefined geographic areas outlined in the Fire Management Plans.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Unknown</edomv>
            <edomvd>A fire event whose incident type was not reported from the original reporting agency.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Out of area response</edomv>
            <edomvd>Multiple resource response to a wildfire incident. This term applies exclusively to wildfire incidents.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Complex</edomv>
            <edomvd>Two or more individual incidents located in the same general area which are assigned to a single incident commander or unified command.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Map_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Mapping ID.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><rdom>
            <rdommin>1</rdommin>
            <rdommax>99999999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Map_Prog</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Mapping program/protocol the fire was mapped with.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><udom>Examples: MTBS, RAVG, BAER, NPS</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Asmnt_Type</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Fire mapping assessment label (Initial (SS) (SS=single scene), Initial, Extended, Extended (SS) (SS=single scene), Emergency, or Emergency (SS)).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Initial</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired shortly after fire containment.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Initial (SS)</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired shortly after fire containment. No pre-fire image was available; assessment based on NBR.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Extended</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired during seasonal peak-of-green after fire containment.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Extended (SS)</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired during seasonal peak-of-green after fire containment. No pre-fire image was available; assessment based on NBR.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Emergency</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired during active incident or immediatly after fire containment.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Emergency (SS)</edomv>
            <edomvd>Imagery aquired during active incident or immediatly after fire containment. No pre-fire image was available; assessment based on NBR.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BurnBndAc</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Number of acres mapped.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>1</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1183539</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BurnBndLat</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Latitude of the mapped centroid of fire perimeter.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>17.957</rdommin>
            <rdommax>70.139</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BurnBndLon</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Longitude of the mapped centroid of fire perimeter.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-165.881</rdommin>
            <rdommax>-65.35</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Ig_Date</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Date of fire ignition (from source fire occurrence databases).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><udom>Example: 9/30/1992</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Pre_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Landsat or Sentinel pre scene ID.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><udom>Example: 503803520040723</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Post_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Landsat or Sentinel post scene ID.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Example: 701503620081007</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Perim_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Landsat or Sentinel perimeter scene ID. Used to help delinate perimeter of an Extended or Extended (SS) assessment. Not always utilized sometimes field will be populated, others not.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Example: A15RVQ20190514</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>dNBR_offst</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The mean dNBR value sampled from an unburned area outside the fire perimeter.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>-9999 or 9999</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Data</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
            <rdommax>9999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>dNBR_stdDv</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The standard deviation of the mean dNBR value sampled from an unburned area outside the fire perimeter.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>-9999 or 9999</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Data</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
            <rdommax>9999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NoData_T</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>No data threshold (in dNBR index values; NBR index units for single scene assessments).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>-9999 or 9999</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Data</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
            <rdommax>9999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>IncGreen_T</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Increased greenness threshold (in dNBR index values; NBR index units for single scene assessments).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>-9999 or 9999</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Data</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
            <rdommax>9999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Low_T</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unburned/Low threshold (in dNBR index values; NBR index units for single scene assessments).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>-9999 or 9999</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Data</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv><rdom>
            <rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
            <rdommax>9999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Mod_T</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Low/Moderate burn severity threshold (in dNBR index values; NBR index units for single scene assessments).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>-9999 or 9999</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Data</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv><rdom>
            <rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
            <rdommax>9999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>High_T</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Moderate/High burn severity threshold (in dNBR index values; NBR index units for single scene assessments). </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>-9999 or 9999</edomv>
            <edomvd>No Data</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv><rdom>
            <rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
            <rdommax>9999</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Comment</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>As needed comments or notes provided by the mapping analyst to the end user.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Producer Defined</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><udom>Text</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>GS ScienceBase</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>Denver Federal Center, Building 810, Mail Stop 302</address>
          <city>Denver</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal>80225</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-275-8747</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>sciencebase@usgs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>This product is produced from MTBS geospatial information prepared by the U.S. Geological Survey EROS and USDA Forest Service. By taking receipt of these files via electronic file transfer methods, you understand that the data may be updated due to the availability of additional data or revision of existing data. Represented features may not be in an accurate geographic location. The U.S. Geological Survey EROS and USDA Forest Service make no expressed or implied warranty, including warranty of merchantability and fitness, with respect to the character, function, or capabilities of the data or their appropriateness for any user's purposes. The U.S. Geological Survey EROS and USDA Forest Service reserve the right to correct, update, modify, or replace this geospatial information without notification.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform><digtinfo>
          <formname>Digital Data</formname>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt><onlinopt><computer><networka><networkr>https://doi.org/10.5066/P9IED7RZ</networkr></networka></computer></onlinopt></digtopt></digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20200818</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>MTBS Project Manager</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>47914 252nd Street</address>
          <city>Sioux Falls</city>
          <state>SD</state>
          <postal>57198</postal>
          <country>US</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-252-4547</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>https://www.mtbs.gov/contact</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Biological Data Profile of the Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001.1-1999</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
